all right
the um welcome john it's great to see
you again guys
yeah it's always good to see you i just
did you i actually just did your um
uh wow boy it looks like i'm really
opening up
the results of my meditation look
i just came from john's class
the uh the beginning of the
of the tai chi chuan that yeah
i love i'm i'm really loving the way
that you're layering it
it's like the lay the just the layering
it
in itself has just been
insightful about the way it works
together and the one
the one that was really uh evocative for
me
and um has been has been lingering
with me was when was when you went
all right prajna and
meta right in breath right prajna out
breath
meta and then your ground the passenger
meta
yeah and the figure ground in that sense
at some point they'll interpenetrate
each other i was just like
that just it it it not only just was the
experience because it wasn't like i
wasn't experiencing that before but it
made something distinct
and that distinction has been popping up
everywhere right
yeah but just that layering of those
things over
the course of time just in themselves as
a
yields yields in sight
thank you i mean that's uh yeah that's
what i learned from my teacher at the
ecology of practice so yeah
sorry for uh interrupting you i just
wanted to make sure that just a few
people are listening
the term so the yeah the the uh
when you're doing the in-breath you feel
your chest expanding you're doing meta a
contemplative practice you're exhaling
you're doing the pasta
and then like as you said in in project
you're alternating between meta and
vipassana and then
at some point it goes from instead of
being out and in and out and in it goes
to being
like you said all at once
inter-penetrating and that's
a non-dualistic uh a very um
active and dynamic non-dualistic state
yeah that is
very conducive for transformation right
and then
yeah so yeah that though
i'm glad you recognize that because this
idea of build like
layering practices on each other into an
ever
uh growing um ecology that was
like that was the deep lesson that i got
from the people who taught me
because i was taught the past meta and
tai chi chuan
together and so
yeah now that we've done uh
a much more uh i guess more than
more than often it's done much more
embodied forms of the pasta and meta
and then taking them into prajna now
we're turning as you said towards the
the tai chi chuan direction i'm teaching
people
um jan zhang which is standing in each
one
movement these are parts of chi kung the
cultivation of the qi
and that's also to layer back on uh
because
you probably noticed that a lot of these
exercises are now inactive
they're an active imaginal exercises yes
we're enacting the right the expansion
like just like in the in the centering
and
and then again what happens is when you
get sort of the chi experience you get
that
again neither in or out right neither
moving or at rest it's beyond all of
that
and then that and the prajna starts to
do this with each other
yes that's the whole point the whole
point is to give it
the the layering that's the mutual
affording
uh is to create a a living structure
that will take on a life of its own yeah
it is and it's interesting like so when
we went into the
tai chi tuan it was just from those
layers
again it was just one of those things of
oh okay here's the out
and the in and and in that whole
it just starts to hit these these built
up
layers of distinctions and anchors that
are
in the body right it's just it's it's
really great
i'm really appreciating it john i know a
lot of other people are too
well thank you yeah there's more like
for example the first
check the gen john we did of embracing
the tree right
and then well i guess they go in the
review on wednesday and friday
you know that's also connects to the you
know the core fourth of a passenger
you're making sure you're centered and
you rooted like a tree
right and so embracing of the tree is
the participatory knowing of
you know what it's like to be a tree
almost a perspectival noise
and so like there's yeah there's lots
there's lots going on it's meant to be
like music
it's meant to be layered vertically like
in harmony and then layered like you
know
uh horizontally like in melody and so
the melody and the harmony the
musicality of intelligibility
is being explicated and enhanced you
know
um articulated and afforded by that
whole process so
interesting so yeah so interesting in in
the
and also the the lectio divina
oh the lecture yeah like just that
that sense of bringing all those ways of
knowing into
into like basically an idea a like a
poem into a distinction right
it have how all that fits together and
one of the things i wanted to
you know wanted to just it's a bunch of
things i want to talk with you i
wanted to talk with you about your
experience of taking the group into
dialogues
at legal wisdom they talk about um
lectio divina uh and it's
in the the sense of what we talked about
last time how
and i've been thinking about this since
we talked about it which is
your prediction that once people start
doing
lectio divina in the in a group that
there's something about that
just makes sense that that'll naturally
open into dialogues
right and that's actually had me think
about
about what's happening with when you
read
a text right and then what's happening
when
we look at that like translate that into
dialogues or dialogue when it goes into
dialogues right
of of you know
who's what's the text right who's the
reader
right like what's the meaning of the
text and start to play with those
metaphors
well i'm happy to talk about all of this
yeah
i mean lectio is an example
a really important example of what i
call a bridging practice
in the ecology of practices
so there are practices like we've just
we were talking about where you can
layer them onto each other and then they
interpenetrate
yeah and they enter forward but then
there's also practices that are designed
to bridge between other practices
and so the way i see
in practice um lectio
is it takes you from the silence
of acidic practice and moves you into
speech but a kind of speech that then
prepares you as you're saying for
dialogues which is
inter speech right um and so
lexia for me is this really
living bridge uh between the
logos and meditation and contemplation
or between logos and prajna if you were
to ask me
for sort of the ontological designations
yeah right
because pr so praja what what what is
prajna actually
like what does it mean again what does
it indicate so
uh it's uh wisdom um
yeah but no but but and but in uh
in a sense i i i was talking about this
when i was talking with andrew and chris
in a way that sort of integrates
aristotle's notion to both sofia and
from these cysts
right it's so it's it's
it's an active dynamic it's it's when
your fluid intelligence the intelligence
in action in interaction right uh
is because has become a self-liberating
uh so that dynamic of being
self-organizing right
is self-organized it's autopoetic in
that it is self-organized
to seek out right um
a way in which it's self-transcending
self-liberating
so you're being free from foolishness
parasitic processing but you're also
being freed for
free free to flourish connect more
deeply
so and prajna so
that's its functionality it's
phenomenology is
that it's a state that emphasizes
i would say this is non-traditional
language so
clearly i'm speaking i think the
non-duality that is
traditional is a way of foregrounding
the
transductivity the coupledness right um
the dynamic
co-emergence of agent and arena um
and so that the point about prajna
especially if you see you see it the way
i present
um in the course as the stereoscopic
fusion
of metacontemplation and
meditation what it's actually doing
right is
it's it's it's sort of putting you in a
space in
uh so in meta i'm becoming aware of the
existential moding right and then
the past now i'm moving to a place of
disidentification
that makes insight possible so i get the
deepest possible
insights from vipassana but what are
they restructuring well
they're restructuring what meta is
making available to me which is my
existential mode
so i'm not getting an intellectual
instinct i'm getting an existential
insight
but it's not a one-moment insight it's
like in the flow state i'm getting a
cascade of existential insights that
have that aspirational trajectory
yeah that yeah that feedback loop
yep yep so so it's like with prajna is
something like it's wisdom
i keep getting the senses you were
talking about this sense of of this
this affording of uh and for some reason
i was thinking about
um apprehension and
comprehension like yeah it is
but it's also but it's like also
deceptive
it's very perceptive but it's but here
here's
here's let's see there's some
terminology that's helpful here
notice the word you use apprehension so
white has this i have this term for
apprehension right
which is the way so the how your mind
perceives the world is your mind doesn't
really perceive
because what your mind picks up on
are relations and patterns that are
actually not visible or audible
or tactile you're apprehending the real
relations
and then you're perceiving the real
things right
and so prajna is both prehension and
perception
right yes that inner penetration of the
two
right yeah so like no doujin says it
so you're in a state that's beyond
in and out it's beyond in the center
beyond and beneath
it's beyond and beneath in and out it's
mind and body it's beyond and beneath
itself and others it's beyond and
beneath god and nature
and then the idea is in lectio
yeah you bring that into the dharma you
bring that into
like the wisdom teachings as a way of
reading
not for information but reading uh
to entrust yourself to transformation
yeah and so
that gets you into like linking all the
kinds of knowing together
right and then you take that into deal
logos and that's what i mean if we can
get all of the
if we can especially imagine that you
can get what i described in prajna
right presencing itself within
dialogues yeah and got something i think
very profound
totally and it's also it's also in terms
of you know in terms of practices it
seems like
that those the linking right between
those and because you know it's that
common thing of that you always hear
about of like where people can meditate
really well but they get up and the
moment somebody you know doesn't give
them what they want
it all goes away there's something about
i think that dialogos
seems to just bring
just a sense of like bring that into the
realm
of of interaction and
how we go about the world right exactly
and so lectio
is to bring you into interaction right
um
with other people's viewpoints and words
and ideas and then right and then
things like the the chi kung practices
right are
designed to bring you into physical
interaction
with your physical environment and do
your logos
is to bring you into interpersonal and
alts ultimately
inter oncological yeah your actions
right right
and so yeah i that's why
and you've seen some when i teach i
teach that how you come out
of your considered practice is
a part of the practice in fact i think
it's the most important part of the
practice exactly that's why i give
people
another bridging practice which is the
reciting of the five
promises to yourself as a way of
bridging because
you should always be thinking of you're
sitting not as an escape
right not as a vacation but as an
education it's always
meant to be integrated as much as
possible with your everyday
consciousness cognition and communities
every day
right so
to come to that there's a point about
that i get this question often
and it's a good question that's why i'm
happy to answer it again again
people will have to ask me well how are
you how do i know that if i'm doing it
right
and what they mean is they want some
sort of some phenomenological marker
that says
you're doing it right right that's not
where you look
yeah where you actually look is is the
integration happening
are the patterns in your practice are
they starting to emerge naturally
in your life and then as they and
especially
other people notice it right right and
if then
and then does that mean that the pattern
right that the patterns in your life are
also now coming up
in your practice yeah right yes
when when you get the reciprocal opening
that's when you know you're doing it
right there isn't anything
in i mean i can give people guy which i
do i answer a question
you know well if you do like if your
mind is getting really dull and comfy
you're not doing it well if you think
you can help people
but at the level of am i doing this
virtuously because that's what people
are
ultimately up to right not am i just
practicing it sort of efficiently
but am i ultimately cultivating wisdom
and virtue it's like well
you know it's it's it's in the
integration
that's why the layering and the linking
the layering
practices and the linking of practices
is so vital
right so vital and and one see i'm
getting very very passionate about this
one of the things i'm deeply critical of
is the oversimplification
of these kind of practices in the west
where we take all of mindfulness
you know think about the buddha gave
this eightfold path
that is comprehensive of people's lives
and then we
reduce all of that to sort of the
mindfulness aspects
and then we reduce all of the
mindfulness to sitting
in meditation and then we think that
this is going to accomplish
this the same thing as this entire
ecology of practices
i think i think that's a mistake yeah
yeah it's a total mistake
yeah so this this uh
yeah this sense of of of where i think
you've
talked about this before about where
that that uh that self-organization
right the the flow of that the the the
logos of it
right begins to take hold
and gets a life of its own that shows a
speech it shows up and you're listening
it shows up
right and this is what i'm thinking
about with with dialogos
is is that there's a way where we're
exercising in dialogues is like a
practice
right but then there's dialogues in
relationship with your own internal
world and the way that you think and the
way that you relate to
reality and in that that sense of
um this is where it gets really exciting
to look at that logos as a practice
right uh well yeah i'm i'm
so it's got a little bit of breakthrough
actually
well chris and i have been doing a lot
of work and i've been doing
and then i've also been doing i don't
know i've been doing what i'm trying to
do as a cognitive scientist and it comes
off as a little bit arrogant but
it's it's i hope it's not which is you
know
i often try and understand something by
reverse engineering it
right and so as you know
and with your help and peter's help
kristin's help and jordan's help
right and all right i've been taking a
deep look and i've continued to do so
with the help of many people like
gonzalez
uh a whole bunch of people
more like what was the ancient practice
of dialectic
first of all when when you as you as you
followed forward especially when you
followed into the near plateness
dialectic uh goes from dialectic is
simultaneously
interpersonal but like you said it's
also intrapersonal and it's
inter-oncological when people are moving
within the layers here we go again with
the layers of the ontology
and they're also right so and chris and
i have used the metaphor of
the interpersonal being the horizontal
dimension
and the intra ontological being
the the vertical dimension
and so just one more thing just
uh it might be helpful for people i'm
finding it helpful and chris and i are
really trying to make this
because i want to bring out something
you brought you made there because
i've been thinking about this a lot and
maybe more careful with our terms it
could help
yeah right notice like we were talking
about the difference between when you
do something you do a practice but
especially if you do it in a layered and
linked way
right the self-organization can even
become auto-poetic
right it can take on a life of its own
yes yes okay
so i'm trying to observe the term
dialectic
for practices that i can do even
layering and linking
and then via logos for when it takes
when the practice
does that shift and takes on its own
right
right so the way i i now try to say it
is
i practice dialectic to realize the
logos
yeah yeah okay that makes sense yeah
it's like we're putting the logs of the
propositions up yes yes
and then lighting and like you get them
you start rubbing them together and
like dialogue dialectic right
and at some point it just sparks right
it becomes greater yeah
yeah you're making use of all kinds of
paraplegia and platonic
right absolutely and so
at rebel wisdom i got to practice
uh with people um mostly what i would
call
the horizontal dimension dialectic
but i was also able to start bringing in
a bit of the
vertical although um a lot of the
vertical also needs to be done
by individuals on their own but uh but
that
i i was getting both of those and what
was interesting
uh was also to see like where and
when right as to use your metaphor
it sparks and catches fire and you can
see people starting to get caught up
yeah and so part of the engineering was
to think well
we already know some of the conditions
that will get people into the flow state
and the flow state is when i practice
something and then it takes on
it catches fire right so i was trying to
bring that
in and then i mean and i talked about
i made reference to all of you guys um
at rebel wizard repeatedly
because then what i've been trying to do
is go over
and you know chris and i are doing sort
of a very high level theory
and then i'm doing very i don't i don't
like to call it low level but more
grounded
practice and then and part of that
practice has been to constantly review
all of what we've been doing and what
i've learned from you
and what i've learned from you know
other people
and trying to draw it together into a
fairly doable
uh layering and linking of practices
that that i call dialectic that gets us
into dialogue
so so yeah and um
i mean if you want at some point i can
go over what that looks like concretely
but what happened what happened at rebel
wisdom
at least from my perspective uh was
it was it was very successful um
because there was one more sort of uh
turn of the theoretical wheel that
happened just before
rebel wisdom and it came up in my
discussion with you if you remember our
last one
um it is you know that the fact that all
the platonic dialogues are about virtue
is not a coincidence yeah right because
virtue
is the place in which all of these
things come together
um and that yeah so that
the that the the dialectic
if it's trying to become dialogues
should always
be both trying should have virtue as a
topic
while exemplifying virtue as a response
to that topic yeah
yeah and so what what happened
i'll just go through what it looks like
now again
i i i was clear i had to present a
truncated thing because i
see this as actually something that
people should do
after they've done right meditation
contemplations touch each one and
circling
they have to have done those four things
i think before they do this
right but what am i going to do wow
before i teach you right so i couldn't
do any of that so i had to present sort
of
this right but i want that
now i can say it we've got some time to
explore it like people
they should have to be doing a
meditative practice a contemplative
practice a moving mindfulness practice
and they have to be doing circling those
are the things they have to be doing
right now let's say that that is given
okay that's a big given i get it but
let's say let's let's presume that
that's the case so then
how it works right is that sorry
one more thing which was coming up also
in the discussion from andrew chris
sorry for doing this this is right on
the edge of my thinking
and there's all these people that are
helping me right now i want everybody
included
right yeah yeah the other thing is which
is how do we bring in
something how do we make it more
socratic and how do we bring in
argumentation
yeah okay so at rebel wisdom i couldn't
fully bring in the argumentation
i'll talk about how i did that recently
i rebel wisdom
it goes like this so people you break
them up into groups of four
okay and this is influenced by um
laura bateson's ideas of warm data and
the one data labs right
so what happens is uh that group they
decide collectively what
virtue is going to be their topic let's
say it's honesty
yeah okay so what happens is one person
it goes first
and the person picks somebody who's
going to be their
an initial amplifier and so the first
and you don't make
propositions you make proposals you
don't state propositions
you commit yourself to a proposal and
you need it in both ways
not only do you grasp the semantic
content but you mean it like when you
ask somebody did you mean what you just
said
like are you committed to it okay so
full meaning
so that's why i say say i propose that
don't say
honesty is say i propose that
right so i propose that honesty is x
okay
and then the amplifier their job is
stuck and this is like from the true
person the past exercise
and but you'll see circling right and
then you'll see why circling would
really matter to this
person who's amplifying they're not
supposed to in any way
challenge at the amplification stage
what they do is they well i noticed that
when you
were when you when you first talked
about uh
honesty you were leaning forward you're
leaning back and you know you know
what's in my mind for there is you
because that's what you do you do that
all you notice what people are doing
you notice they're gestured and this
also came from the
work i did on the focusing well you
clenched your hand there go back
clench your hand what's that like what's
like going on for you right now right
and so can you tell me more and oh you
were started there what's happening
while you're smiling
so the the amplifier is trying to get
the person to
become more reflectively aware of their
participation in the proposal right
right right
amplify amplify amplify
then at some point the proposal the
proposer is going to get towards kind of
an emporia
they're going to go all right yeah and
then and then
and what happens is you know and now the
amplifier
speaks it switches to what i call
appreciation
the amplifier has to first say what they
what they really got
right so they have to repeat back to the
person who spoke
this is what i heard you saying and they
have to do that until the first person
says yeah you got me
you understood right so appreciation in
the sense of understanding
and then and then this is what i value
about what you said this is what is good
this is what but this is what i hadn't
thought of before this is what i had
forgotten
right so they do that they do the
appreciation okay
right then they are going to
turn to another the third person
what they're going to do is they're
going to do
anticipation of their proposal they
don't jump into their proposal
and what they do is they have to say
this is where they are now challenging
but they're not going to actually
confront the person
they're going to right so what they're
going to say is okay
this is what i thought was missing in
that proposal
all right here's a part of honesty that
i really think is important that was
missing
or here's what was mysterious in that
proposal i found that strange
or odd right and then finally
and i i emphasize people don't put the
emphasis on this one
you're not trying to be right you're
trying to come into
right relationship yeah yeah right yeah
you're neither attacked neither merely
attacking nor merely agreeing
yeah this is the mistake and i try to
break it back up into mistaken
how the proposition is wrong but is
there an assumption
is there a way the person was taking yes
you want to call into question
right okay talk about that for a bit and
now the other the third person amplifies
the second person doing the anticipation
right
right and then until the until that that
second person can now say okay now i'm
ready
i propose that honesty is this and then
they get amplified
and then at some point they stop and
then the third person does the
appreciation
with them and then turns to the fourth
and does anticipation until they make a
proposal
and then it cycles all the way around in
the four so you do that until
everybody does this yeah and then you
get
groups the groups that come back would
it be good to at least have four groups
right to come back and do a common space
and and
hopefully usually almost always they've
done different virtues
honesty right remember you're like when
you're amplifying you're trying to pick
up on how the person
is exemplifying not just expo
doing exposition right right so right
and because it's virtue people it really
bridges for people
so the four groups come back and now
they're all together and now
this is what they answer they don't
answer in closure but this is what they
they go into dialogues you ask them okay
what is virtue
that is what is honesty not what is
current and what happens is
they do the thing where they zoom into
their particular virtue when they're
better
and then zoom out and zoom in and zoom
out and zoom in
and zoom out and what happens right
is they get into they get into the logos
and they get a sense of
right they get a sense of the moreness
and the suchness that
they're like virtue is so complex and
dynamic
and they feel that they've come into a
better relationship with
and then and i didn't have time to do
that then i i
like what you could do is you could just
have open reflection
after that process or you know i thought
that there might be
another transitional thing where people
go back just into
circling and they just go back into
circling then they
that's all just resonating and vibrating
for them
oh yeah that's how the process ends yeah
that's interesting
so that's the horizontal but you see had
a bit of it had a bit of the vertical in
it right right
with the ontological yeah absolutely i
like that that sense of starting with
something like
virtues particular virtues and then the
meta
idea that unites those right and going
in between structurally that just seems
really
deeply
penetrative yeah what i want to say
right now it's really important to me
because
i care about you and i care about your
work i hope
you see your influence in all of this i
hope you see
i've tried to incorporate a lot of what
i've learned to you and try to do it
justice
i hope you feel that oh yeah oh totally
yeah
yeah absolutely well no that's important
to me yeah i really i really do
i really do big time big time and i feel
that too
i feel that in our in our friendship in
our
um in the way that you you continually
note it
but also just in the in the fact
of the mutual kind of penetration of
these ideas and
you know like we're constantly talking
on text and
and it's a it's a it's a that's how it
lives for me
and you do a great job of
well i saw that interpenetration well i
didn't see it i heard it
i listened to you when you were on my
discord server um
thank you for doing that by the way that
was wonderful all right
yeah i i i just saw that that was
wonderful
so so anyways you like matt i'm not
like again imagine individuals who were
doing
like the mindfulness ecology the
meditation contemplation
moving which economy the tai chi there
and then
as you said then they bridge from that
into lexia yeah
and then maybe out of that a particular
virtue right
comes up right and then they take that
into the logos
right right you can see how that whole
yeah would just be very very powerful
for people
very very quickly absolutely and even if
you think about it too it'd be
if you you run a few of those and then
just think about like okay
so how would that just catch when
somebody just starts to talk about their
life
yes yeah and like you don't even have to
i would imagine
you don't even have to put many frames
around it after a few cycles of those
people are probably just you'll probably
notice that people go it's they're
amplifying they start doing all the
components
right yeah totally totally
and and i would hope that they would
also start to notice
how the various practices interact each
other
right they would start to listen perhaps
when people are speaking more
more poetically right and then they
might bring the mindfulness to bear
because one of the promises we make is
the promise right
to use speech mindfully carefully
lovingly right
right and so and right and then they
think oh but
as i'm listening like does this person
like it's lexio divina
i'm also practicing the mindfulness and
then they they're also
like looking for what but what is being
exemplified here what virtue is coming
again i could see but that that is what
happens right yeah
and then the point is we we get right
not just propositions we get the
proposals of
ways of being right gratuitous and ways
of life being exemplified
so now the more recent piece i did
and this is something i mean i want to
talk to you about and
but and it was it's just come out on
andrew's channel it will come out on my
channel
on friday is um
how to bring something like
argumentation in and so what i was
thinking is instead of just
a sequence of propositions right what it
is
is it's a sequence of proposals
right that logos that gather together
and mutually afford each other
until right right and then what you do
is you basically
make a proposal and then you do some
theologians about it
and then the person makes another
proposal what you might let them do this
is what i did is
sort of present the the sequence of
proposals and then you go back and do
via logos
and you try and sort of jazz your way
from one proposal to the next
right until they all come to belong
together and mutually afford
right so that's what i did so i had a
particular argument
um the argument i was making an argument
that
virtue is the beauty of wisdom and what
that means and how to understand that
and then what i did was i had a sequence
of proposals
and then and then we did we did sort of
deal logos around and
so you do the logos invite you allow me
this metaphors around
each proposal and then between each
proposal
until you get this intuitive a kind of
you know uh uh of proposals where you're
seeing all the proposals in each
and each and all right right approximate
proposals
yes i'm seeing t-shirts
that's awesome well it's also the thing
that you just laid out there
i mean on some level i bet
i mean you're exemplifying i mean isn't
this what
what you've been doing on in all your
discussions
right is you've been doing just that or
you kind of have an idea and you're
playing with it right
like even before all of this was
specifically formulated like
the way that you did but it seems like
that's what i
sense is that you there's something that
kind of emerges and you have an idea
maybe it's this and this and this like
oh yeah
and then we go into dialogue about it
right and then
something something happens and it it
puts the next thing so if like we just
watched all of the discussions
i wonder i bet we we see that pattern
that goes
goes throughout i think so i think
that's exactly right and that's
i mean that has been sort of the the
teacher guiding me
in in this whole process is to try and
see what patterns are
taking shape yeah right what principles
are coming into process via those
patterns
and what processes are being principled
in those patterns
and seeing all of that working together
so that's what i keep looking for
you know here's a pattern yeah what what
principle is it bringing in
and what process is it going into well
here's a pattern what process is it
bringing
is it is it is it explicating and
bringing a normativity
you know so i always think of this
emanation of principle
with this emergence of process and that
and the logos is the patterning right
totally so that's what that's what i'm
looking for yeah that's sort of
the method i use when i'm trying to get
a sense about this and then
and then as a cognitive scientist what i
do is i reverse engineer i say okay what
do i know about human cognition
yeah right and how could i fit how could
i articulate
these practices yeah such that i could
fit them best
to i could reverse engineer them for
granted
right that's what i've been doing
totally yeah absolutely
and so it's interesting like as it's
coming out it's
as you're formulating it right it's
interesting
there's that sense of there's that sense
of in a certain sense like
like i'm bringing it like more to your
awareness right now well isn't that what
you've been doing on some level all the
way through it's like
here's that that thing about then you
talked about the teacher right that def
that invisible deft hand that's
that on one level it looks like um
i was thinking about this with with
rapport
the difference between creating rapport
and then the experience of rapport
is more like it's revealed right it's
like yes
because there's always that sense of
like when i'm in a rapport with somebody
one you find yourself into it but it's
not this sense of like i have
created something or no something it's
more like
oh there you are it's like oh
i think that's right and that i mean
that's so chris and i
well you've read the the chapter in that
scene
and we talked about this as the movement
from logos little l to
logos right so the idea here is
right the moreness of intelligibility
logos with a big all the way
right the logos that ultimately is part
of ontol logos
the logos of being right that's always
precipitated into
right it's impregnated into our spoken
uh our spoken logos and our gestural
logos
right and so what would right
and then what we do in the deal logos is
we like it's the conception the
pregnancy
is right it's developed and the midwife
and then what you're doing is
you're giving birth to the the the logos
but it actually finds you and you and
i've talked about this
and that that's where the virtue comes
in because virtue is ultimately
right every virtue is a way of being
wise in a particular situation it's a
way of refining
the logos in speech act yeah the logos
of being
and so that's that's that was my attempt
to
disclose because i was talking to chris
about this i say
guy is always doing that and that's not
a complaint by the way
right the guy is always doing that where
he's saying look at how we got here
a place we couldn't get to on our own
but it's but
what we discovered was always there
that's why i point i brought back
that term inventio yeah right right uh
yeah that kerry uses in
uh the book on august and invention of
the inner cell this invention means both
to make and to discover
yeah right and it's that sense so what i
think it is
is again like the way dialectic makes
possible but it isn't the making of
the logos right i think the via logos
the dialogue
part the logos between us right right
that
that that that's the making part but
what is discovered
right is the logos that was already
there always yes
they're under underneath there
absolutely absolutely concealed that
whole thing about like
concealed and revealed and the
hiddenness
yeah is the is the is not that
not the uh you know the castell
hiddenness of where it's like you
conquer everything and then you even
conquer hiddenness right
it's more like the hiddenness is what we
follow the whole time
right and when it reveals see this is
the thing about it like i think
one of the things i love about rilka and
like poetry really is it has this
ability to reveal
you could say the unknown without
um without uh
making it known but it retains its
unknown
it's mysterious mysteriousness in its
disclosure
right so it becomes right so
so i think about this as a trajectory of
transformation
that always ascends metanamically right
so the logos the dynamic unfolding of
the logos
gives us a sense of trajectory in a
transformation
but that ultimately is a finger that's
pointing towards
the logos right right metanamically
it's not separate from it it's it's a
medium it it participates in it but it
also points beyond itself in its
participation this is so
neoplatonic right totally so that's
that's how
so i think of the movement that happens
both the movement out of
my own subjectivity into the wee space
right and then right and then and then
the movement of that whole space
right that don't that that trajectory
that's that's me that's us
me and us pointing with our whole being
right towards the logos but the ability
to point
embodies the logos it's not something
separate from it
yes exactly exactly exactly and that
sense of
of where you eat you in that um i really
liked your last
video with uh chris and and
and andrew is it not andrew yeah andrew
sweeney yeah
um where you guys are talking about
you i think you said something in it
kind of in passing but it kind of struck
me of of where how plutonius
puts the you know the meta logos right
it's all kind of like in in this
in this infinite all at once-ness right
yes but we have to
basically take that in dialogues and
bring that into sequence right yes
that that's that's the function of soul
yeah
that's the in platinus that that that's
soul takes what it so intellect is
the all at once right like um
like here like
how each virtue actually presupposes the
other virtues
and that right so if i'm going to be
honest i also have to be courageous
right right if i'm going to be honest
right i i also need
to know how to be kind right because
right because if i'm just honest without
kindness i'm not actually honest i'm
just brushed and cruel
right and so right and then and you can
think about how each
virtue is just like i say how do i be
wise
in this here now-ness well to be wise
here now is to be courageous
to be wise here now is to be kind to be
wise here now is to be reverential
so again the titus that's the that's the
news that's the intellect
right all the verb all the principles of
intelligibility all the virtues
are there he often compares them like
it's like theorems
in an argument and this is why spinoza
is so important they all
all interpenetrate and interdefine all
at once that's
news and then news like that all at
once-ness the
one uh the the one in many
points towards the one right right
totally so it points up towards the one
but as you said it also it's also
it emanates it affords it makes possible
the the dionya yeah but the dianoya is
the neue but it's in motion right diana
and the
via logos are right and that's soul and
so what happens
that's what we're talking about in the
in both that
uh dialogue in the previous one where
soul is the mediator
between muchness sorry between moreness
and sections yeah how we participate in
the inexhaustible
right yes yes but how that comes into
the non-categorical non-repeatable here
now-ness
right of like the sort of the
mystery at the court of time yeah yes
yeah is put into a relationship the
mystery at the core
of eternity the mystery of participation
and the mystery of individuation are
brought into relationship to each other
yeah like like like almost almost like
this deeper sense of space and time
mutually penetrating each other right
yes yes
yeah eminence and emergence eternity and
time
yeah this is why the stuff i'm the work
i'm doing on aerogena right now is so
important because
that he he's the guy that turns
dialectic
yeah right into a like a
metaphysical principle he sees reality
in in this kind of neoplatonic dialogue
heterogena erogena
yeah do you remember here here's a
really good
introductory book this one right here
oh john scottis oh yes okay yes yes yeah
regina yeah because he's doing that in
this whole yeah i mean that's exactly
what he's
and he did it he is way before his time
right
oh yeah he's like 900 i think
yeah yeah so it's it's unfair
neoplatonic dialectic is not hegelian
dialectic and it's unfair to
attribute it to regina because he's way
before
something much more comprehensive and
transformative and the interesting thing
is the paris appeal the division of
nature is actually written as a dialogue
yeah it's actually it's presented as a
dialogue and it's interesting because
it's presented as an interpersonal
dialogue
between two people right basically the
guru and the students
right but it's also there's four parts
the four divisions so it's also an
ontological dialogue or
four divisions right that's like he and
he's
it exemplifies uh like turning what
we're talking
about into on one poll
a comprehensive way of life and on the
other pole
a correspondingly comprehensive
worldview
that's what's happening in his work yeah
god that's good it's amazing so this is
also kind of gets you another
kind of thing that i was i was i've been
thinking about
as well is you're thinking about like
okay so what is that and i think you
said it
when it when you when you said soul is
the
is the is the is the mediator between
these two
which had brought me to the it reminded
me of this thing i've been
i think i texted you about it too with
with chris about like well
if we look at it well what is what is
the medium
like medium of this and i started to
think about play with that
about um you know
uh like in painting right oil painting
right and what like in a certain sense
like and it's the right medium in in in
comparison because
acrylic i can't work with acrylic
because it it does
basically the same thing it's hard to
tell the difference once it's all dried
but it's
you can't it it's too constraining with
time
right so you have to like you know with
oil it stays wet so you
you can really you can paint it you can
blend the colors and work with it on the
canvas versus on the
you know have it ready made and then
paint it in and then i was thinking
about
what a medium does right the oil does is
it
on one level it holds everything
together right
it holds the paint together right but in
holding it together it also releases
it into appearance but yet the music
itself to the degree that it's doing its
job
when it releases the paint into
appearance while holding it together it
also
itself simultaneously withdrawals into
that releasement
right yes and so i was just thinking
about like
what so what would be the oil right
of the dialogical dialogues
painting you know and
it's interesting to kind of think about
that right
well i have an answer um um
i think i think i do too let's let's see
what this is this is what i kind of came
up with and i was thinking about like
well i think
what probably makes it what it what it
is
is that that in some level
the realization right of the dialogue
and the dialogue
right is is actually where
where that which withdrawals on some
level in
in the oil it it goes through
it realizes itself in
in um like kind of a trans substitution
right
or something like that like it's like
it's like it's almost like the
the medium is the always already the
case
the invisible deftan that on some level
at the top
kind of goes ah it all makes sense you
know
on some level i think that's right
um phenomenologically
um yeah it's about it's about the
it's about what we've talked about about
the you know phenomena the shining
report that's always the withdrawal
right functionally and then the other
the other time too the other thing it
also has me think about like well
okay well well what is the medium though
right what is the phenomena right
and this is where i start to touch it
when i feel into that i start to
i started to touch into uh
uh how do you say it yeah
this sense of emptiness of of
there's something about that as well so
the emptiness
that i think is yeah
okay so i want to say so i'll propose
over here
and then we'll look for convergence
we'll do we'll do the argument
because i think the medium the thing
that glues like the paint but
also becomes transparent so we see
through it i think it's relevance
realization because what relevance
realization does
is it makes the framing that then
withdraws precisely because it's
transparent and it affords me looking
through it
right i do right precisely because i'm
seen
by means of it it draws into
right into the grounding of my
intelligibility
and then but you have to remember that
relevance realization isn't
mine right it's a way in which the world
and me are co-emerging together
so i think the emptiness is the fact
of this deep coupling the coupling
that's at the mystery of my freshness
which is what you know in a lot of
buddhist effects you get the sense of
you know the pure mind which is the mind
that isn't
is is the the existing power to become
any particular form
but is no form itself that's that's
relevance realization
and that that mystery of the sense of
suchness right
is what keeps me coupled to the off
in love with the moreness of reality
so the moreness the combinatorial
explosion of information
yeah right and the ongoing
open-ended that's the emptiness no
essence to it
open-endedness of the relevance
realization
the mystery of the suchness
they come together right they come
together in my framing of the world
that and the emptiness is the mystery of
the moreness
the culminatorial explosive nature
reality the mystery of the suchness
the open-endedness at the open-ended
evolution of my relative of relevance
realization
and those are the two coupled together
yeah and that
in that in taking your proposal right
so the the so relevance realization
is what you're proposing is the medium
of this right yes is relevance
realization
and what i what
the background the more like the the
background is like the emptiness
right and and in the foreground
is the suchness right yeah i would say
that
or exactly how you said it i would say i
would say that the background is the
section is the background
is your capacity for individuation your
capacity for here now fitting
yourself to the situation yeah but the
world is not
the world impregnates each situation but
it's always
more than any situation yeah right yeah
so
this is always reinventing itself
right in the in the face of the world
always
unpacking itself always being more both
diachronically
and synchronically both horizontally and
vertically
and then and then relevance realization
is the process
of that being realized over and over and
over and over again that's why i use the
word realization
yeah because it's simultaneously like
detection
and adaptive fitting and it's also
actualization and coming into being
i'm trying to get both this objective
and objective polls
of this process by using the word
realization totally because it's like
it's like because the realization i
really got the sense of like this is why
it's the media because the realization
is like what i'm hearing you say is
what's realized
immediately brings everything together
and then if you ask like well what's
realized right what is the realization
like what realized this realization
right and you look back
you end up back there but in that
process
i there's a sense of how world-making
that is
right exactly exactly this is ultimately
right it's about how things stand out
exist
within being where being is that right
the
intelligibility that reaches to the
horizons of intelligibility
totally and that was yes so and so and
then
of course naturally it's like what's
that glow beyond the horizon
and then you end up back you and so in
some level you
you you in in moving towards that glow
and realizing it
um the thing that
yeah this is why it's the the
individuation this is why
and we're still in the like just to keep
it you know this is we're still in the
amplification part of
i think right like of course i just
thinking about tillich like the like
participation individuation tension
right it's like how this is mirror guy
hang on a second you're you're frozen
just now perfect oh let's see
okay get back okay cool cool great
cool i just try to be yeah the gestures
are so important right yeah
that sense of uh of of
that there's that quality of where when
you
when you have a passion for something
right and you
you just engage with it in some sense
it's like there's
there's that experience of where you're
not thinking about yourself
however at some point that you're
you it's a co-constitution where you're
in
your face articulated by what you've
been looking at right
and then you realize you realize the
whole time that it's been this mutually
shaping yeah well
that but and that's christopher is it
christopher moore
but more the the socratic self-knowledge
that's his basic argument
he says that what socrates tries to show
people
is that the the truest deepest kind of
self-knowledge is not gained through
introspection
not gained through right it's not being
through intuition
it's not gained through sort of formal
definition it's gained through
how like your commitment and
participation in
what you just described that that's
where you actually
know yourself that's why the socratic
self is inherently aspirational
right it's not the romantic self right
you're not expressing it out
right what's happening is it's being
induced from you as the world and it's
how you how your co-emergence
commits to the coherences of the world
the faithfulness the love
right that's where you truly find out
who you are right wow
so the whole point about socratic right
self-knowledge is you cannot find it
except in dialogues
but conjoined to that is
that's where you deeply most truly find
out
who you are
yes through yes
through
like what i'm really kind of getting is
like it's a it's almost impos
you can't you can't be a cartesian oh no
you can't
right like i really kind of get this
sense of this
both both heidegger's kind of
pointing out what
metaphysics both realizes yet hides
like conceals at the same time there's
something about this where
because it's funny when i when we pause
like well what's the
what's the medium well the what is
is the apprehension realization
of everything that's in relationship
with it having being the thing that
it's relating it's like it just deep in
and it ends up outside while seeing
itself inside
but deeper and deeper and deeper and
deeper where there's no
this is where i'm starting to kind of
feel like the realization of the
emptiness
right there's no thing there oh there is
because it's it's it's that which makes
stinginess possible
yeah right yeah and notice how the
relevance realization
is no thickness right because one thing
you can't actually bring into the frame
is the framing anything you bring into
the frame as
as if it was the framing it's it's it's
j you know it's james's i
i me you're always only looking at the
me you can't look at the eye because you
always have to look through the eye
yeah right so there's that and and
notice that relevance realization is
always simultaneously disclosing and
concealing
because i'm i'm finding a subset of the
world relevant and that's shining to me
but i'm also finding although i'm not
finding in fact i'm not even
if i was noticing it i would hit
combinatorial explosion i'm not
i'm intelligently ignorant of vast
aspects of the world
yeah or else i couldn't function
relevance realization is
always a revealing that is a concealing
yeah
that's why it's always evolving because
whatever there is no essence to the
revelation
there's no nothing comes up in the
revelation that captures
right relevance forever it can't work
that way
because it's always a concealing as well
as a revealing
it then has to open up to what was
concealed and reveal again
and then open up to what was concealed
and revealed again and then
and again and again and again and this
is this is soul
this is the dianoya right this is
the attempt the never completable
attempt to disclose the intelligibility
of the world which is combinatorially
explosive
through time and that's what we're doing
well i'm just kind of just i'm just
feeling like a couple of things i'm
feeling the virtue of
of reverence right at play here
and at play right now in the
conversation it's like you just can't
there's something about this sense of
um realizing that this kind of
what's doing the looking what's doing
the talking what's doing the perceiving
is the thing perceived on multiple
levels going up and down
it's like there's the it's like
reverence almost comes to a
point like to a peak like awareness
of finitude and limitation but the
infiniti
yes so so that's drew highland's book
fight
finally i'm reading that reverence right
yeah
but i was thinking of uh heraclitus
right
uh listen not to me but to the logos in
my speech
all things are one right that's the
reverence and it's
that again we talked about it like that
that movement of relevance realization
if it's caught up in the virtue
of reverence that's when you start to
realize
the trajectory and the transframing the
trajectory and the transformation
that extends towards the one but can
never
get there but that's great yeah because
if
if we could get there
we wouldn't be who we are and the world
wouldn't be what it is
yeah boy what a thing to to revere
not having right yeah
like like it's like it's like it's to
revere
what brings in reverence is that i can't
get there
but but the can't get there reveals
it's there the way it's there
right exactly yeah
so robert browning a man's reach
should exceed his grasp or what is a
heaven for
totally this is why i think it's like
every
this is like the two fingers right of
this
of this sense right where michelangelo
into
painting that painting was all before
it's interesting if you think about this
is before
before the the like the reemergence
in a conscious way of the greeks right
of the medicis
right it's like that's all coming up
you know they're digging it out and like
marcio facino and the
like the the the neopl platonus right
behind you what's that painting behind
that painting right there every single
part of it is telling a story i don't
know what the whole story is
you see arrows in there and you see
socrates and socrates is there and he's
off to one
side absolutely the the uh
what was i going to say um
[Music]
oh yes the two fingers about it
it's like before that right it was
always depicted
of like where kind of god is this kind
of distant
patriarchy and man is this kind of
me girly right yearning for god
and all of a sudden but in this it's
like manchester barely like
barely dawning to consciousness and
here's
god right with all the angels like
and and they don't touch right and if if
this is right and it's like if those if
the if they touched
no one would wreck it no one would even
look at it
right it's precisely that they don't
touch
that is that divine kind of
tension right that is so and and
of course even the movie they talk about
like you know it's it's talked about as
the agony and the ecstasy
yes right and i think what we're talking
about is that there's
in some way you know
like you can almost kind of make it kind
of make a
poster of this right of where it's like
agony or ecstasy what's the difference
that makes the difference
right and i think this is what we're
getting at i think the difference
is is something about that thing that
you said
which is the one right you don't want
you don't want to achieve the one right
because it wouldn't be the one
that not like that that aspiration that
reverent
aspiration of like that i think that's
the debt that difference between
the the the experience of agony and the
experience of ecstasy with this
right and i think maybe dialogos
constantly exemplifies that right yeah
i think so i think the emporias
and dia logos are that are the space
that keeps the reverence
and the tension alive yeah but the whole
trajectory
is the sense it's like it's an
asymptotic it's it
i mean i always got the sense in
michelangelo like it's an asymptote
that there's a perpetual closing but
they'll never touch
never right right right absolutely
absolutely
how else would creatures in time get any
intimation of eternity
there's no other way if they get closure
that's not eternity
that's that's an idol in something
that's finite
right and if they it but if there was no
sense of
moving closer this is the epictasis
right of the
of the eastern orthodox some of the
eastern other fathers
god is the perpetual affordance of
self-transcendence
you're genuinely step transcending but
you will never complete it
you will never complete it because
creatures that are in time
only realize the truth of the eternal
truths
in ongoing transcendence
right totally yeah and that comes into
like
this is where i think you know that like
god as a vow
is a as a metaphor makes sense
right because it's there's that quality
of just when you get to know a person
right there's like there is that quality
of like when you genuinely get to know a
person
which is also
the realization of your own shadow is
simultaneously the recognition of
yeah right like because you like in the
in the it's always been that thing about
how do you learn how to listen well
first
you gotta you gotta realize that you
don't right the moment you realize you
don't is when listening
but that's a beautiful example of what
i'm talking about
um the union idea that we can
only know the shadow ultimately
or right initially and ultimately only
dialogically
right uh it's only i cannot
i i it's very hard for me to see how i'm
projecting
unless i'm in dialogue with somebody
at that point you just made that's
brilliant because when you
reject my projection right you
are an enacted emporia that then gives
me the opportunity
for realizing the projection and
in realizing the projection i begin in
that way
to get a sense of my shadow and i think
that's that jungian idea
that's why chris is writing in our
anthology that you're contributing to as
well
right the second chapter he and i are
writing i should say he's first author
on it but we're writing it together
about uh the union practice as
an instance of the logos because exactly
this idea
and that people have gotten too
romantic about young in a sense they
they only sort of think about young
um interest psychically yeah right
but they forget that young is
presupposing that all of this is taking
place
in a therapeutic dialogic context right
that's the frame
in which yeah yeah yeah exactly that
that it's only in something like
therapeutic dialogue that you can
genuinely become aware of the shadow
yeah absolutely and like you
yeah exactly and that's that quality
but that connection between the thou
peeks through right in those moments of
where
it's like where my projection of you or
my my projection on to you
and this is what's interesting is one of
the things i've noticed in in circles
and in working with people in this way
is
a lot of times where things it's it's
the beginning of a big
of a big kind of realization is this
sense of where
i i've always thought about it i really
like the way that objects relations
psychology talks about it like there's
the objective like the self or the
the self is actually always object
subject pull with a with a binding
uh consistent level of affect and where
people kind of like
will go on rants right where all of a
sudden you're talking about like and
they'll just start
addressing a concern that
i don't have that i didn't bring up
right but they're talking about it as if
they're in response and you can start to
tune into that stuff and then you go
like
so many times it's like who are you
talking to
right there yeah yeah and in all that in
that moment there's this
and if they really they catch themselves
in it like oh
who am i talk and it opens the question
right
and that begins yes yes this moment that
they realized that they weren't relating
to the world objectively if you will
as it was they were imp it didn't in
real life but then that
you know begins this whole process of
disclosure
that's right yeah that's important and
so this quality of love it of how
thou unfolds for us it it
it's interesting to think about that
this is where it's like relationship
and it i mean this is you know we
we're we're indistinguishable from our
our sociality our
our you know it's like all the way down
but that sense of
that sense of the of the realization of
myself is
is is allows the the realization of the
other the thou
right yeah that's right
i mean in that you even get that in the
lexia because the lectio
right like it it has to start
you if you're reading for transformation
the vow of the text
it has to right yeah it has to sort of
catch you and
lead you off and beyond but i'm also
thinking practically
what you just said was really important
part of
what like what i was describing as the
amplification process
is for the amplifier to maybe
periodically
ask who are you talking to right now
yeah yes i hadn't thought about that
that's very good
i want to note that down yeah i'm sorry
i don't need to turn away from the
camera
that's great that's a good example
yep
okay that's good and it's it's a and
it's you you kind of feel that question
where yeah that
where that question oh yeah you could
pretty much
you could pretty much ask that at any
point and sometimes the answer is going
to be
you yeah sometimes it's going to be like
sometimes it's going to be like oh is
this
oh i was talking to the person that's
going to get me in trouble at any point
right like like that's what happens with
like a lot of trauma
like like what ends up with a lot of
traumas those things those structures
become something that like haunts people
around
right where they're constantly relating
it to right this brings up
an aspect that i right that's brilliant
that was in the two-person capacity
which i can't teach in the class because
maybe i'll get jesus what you do is you
you don't you you sit you feel that it's
like um you'll you'll see how it belongs
to this whole family of circling and all
the
right you sit um and like
you do for passing it individually with
somebody
present your visual field and then one
person is going to be the speaker
and then the other person is going to be
the amplifying mirror that's part of
where i got this idea from yeah but what
the speaker does
is that they when they're speaking to
the mirror they're talking to somebody
else it's like the empty chair they're
there so they talk to you
so you deliberately project you project
onto your debt
and and the the person that's receiving
they're supposed to be
and this is a really sweet spot you have
to be as fully present as possible
while also being as non-reactive so that
the person can play out the projection
like play it out right and then and then
you switch roles and then you switch
over you keep doing that
but this is a way of getting that in
there what are you talking to right now
who are you talking to right now yeah
that's really good guy thank you for
that
yeah totally and it's uh it's also
there's a sense in it in a way that's
not like there's the projection catching
but there's also this sense of of and
i've started to notice this too this has
been
something that started to articulate
like when you're listening to something
what is it to really
listen to somebody and get yeah it's
it's like
when it's when
you start to notice the possibility
that is that there that's organizing
their attention
right it's like that sense of like
what's going beyond the horizon
because if you think about it there is
that sense that every everything
that i do
is is impregnated with a uh
something's possible right this taliotic
sense of it right and so getting
somebody
isn't listing out what they just said
it's actually kind of getting what is it
that they are so like that's beyond the
horizon
that they it it's it's the thing that's
constituting their very being
right and that when that yeah be lit up
that's the experience of being gotten
right of like
for that experience like oh my god i'm
totally seen
it's like you see the possibility
that that that i can't that everything
that i'm
i am is in relationship with right
i think i'm impregnated by but i'm so
but don't
that's interesting i think that's very
convergent how i i've been trying to
answer that same question
so i think i'm really listening to
somebody
when i'm catching their relevance
realization yeah yeah
where there's a contagion yeah right
like you like
like when we talk about emotional
contagion but it's relevance realization
contagion yeah
and so that right i i'm no longer
outside of your world i i i i'm in it
because
like your relevance realization is to
some degree being
not represented in me it's literally
being instantiated yeah
yeah absolutely because it's it's so i
mean we are so
futural it's like so it's
it's we are so futural like just
everything about
announces this you know this ecstatic
sense of time right
yes and also that quality of just that
sense of when somebody
i mean it's happening and i think it
happens on multiple levels too of just
like there's the personal rest
like about my own character or something
like that right but then there's like
recognition these meta things when when
you get something
there's a way where oh my god something
became possible
but what lights up is you go back
right and you reconfigure that pasta you
re-impregnate that possibility all
through
all the way through your history where
you get a whole new narrative right
yeah in that sense of i think we're
always doing that on some level
and where it gets fixed right and stuck
right are are the
are the places where where we get stuck
right
in a certain sense i agree i agree
so i have uh unfortunately i have to get
going
okay that was wonderful this is really
wonderful thank you so much john
yes thank you guy and uh i'd like to uh
if you could send me the files again my
channel you got it
you upload it on yours first i'll upload
it online what should we call this one
um well
i don't know i i think
i think what we were moving between
talking about dialectic
yeah talking about dialogos we're moving
between talking about the practice
and talking about the process that's
realized i would call it something like
dialectic into the logos yeah all right
sounds good to me okay awesome
all right thank you bye